{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "31_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : This ticket, can I change it to an earlier departure?\nWoman : Yes, I'll check it out.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "31_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : How did you get hurt like this?\n Man : I fell down the stairs and I didn't get seriously hurt.\nWoman : That's a relief. You should be discharged from the hospital quickly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③ ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  다시 생각해 볼게요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  선물을 준비했거든요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  친구한테서 받은 거예요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  생각도 못 했는데 고마워요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Uh, what is this?\nMan : I heard yesterday was your birthday? It's a birthday present.\nWoman : I didn't even think about it, but thank you.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  생각도 못 했는데 고마워요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },        
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  계속 통화 중이지요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  언제쯤 통화가 가능할까요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  담당자 좀 바꿔 주시겠어요?",
            "option_4"      : "④  담당자한테 메모 전해 드릴까요?",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Hello. I'm calling you because of the Internet bill.\nWoman : I'm sorry, but the person in charge is away for a while now.\nMan : When can we talk on the phone?",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  언제쯤 통화가 가능할까요?",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  아니요,제가 닫을게요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  네,잠깐만 열어 주세요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아니요,열지 않았을 거예요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  네,다음부터는 열어 놓을게요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I think the indoor air is a little stuffy. Man: Is that so? Then do you want me to leave the window open?\nWoman : Yes, please open it for a moment.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  네,잠깐만 열어 주세요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  벌써 한 것 같은데요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  내일 해도 괜찮겠어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  그럼 빨리 확인해야겠네요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  팀장님한테 보고하라고 하시던데요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I mean the picnic place. I can check it by tomorrow afternoon, right?\nWoman : No, the team leader told me to do it by today.\nMan : Then I should check it quickly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  그럼 빨리 확인해야겠네요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  즐겨 입는 옷",
            "option_2"      : "②  티셔츠의 기능",
            "option_3"      : "③  티셔츠의 색깔",
            "option_4"      : "④  운동복의 변화",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : This blue T-shirt is something that athletes like to wear. If you sweat, let it out right away, and it won't get wet even if it rains or gets watery.\nWoman : I see. I hope you wear it in the summer like these days.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  티셔츠의 기능",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  빗소리의 종류",
            "option_2"      : "②  빗소리 가주는 효과",
            "option_3"      : "③  마음이 편해지는 공간",
            "option_4"      : "④  달라진 도서관의 모습",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are a lot of people who feel comfortable when they hear the sound of rain. It is said that the sound of rain absorbs the noisy sounds around you, which stabilizes a person's mind and increases concentration. Recently, there has been a space in a library that plays the sound of recorded rain.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  빗소리 가주는 효과",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  닭 가슴살 조리법",
            "option_2"      : "②  다양한 요리 방법",
            "option_3"      : "③  근육에 좋은 음식",
            "option_4"      : "④  닭 가슴살의 장점",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Chicken breast that helps to build muscles. I know it's good for your health, but it's not easy to eat because of the dry feeling. When boiling chicken breast, don't cook it completely, take it out before it's cooked and bake it lightly in a frying pan. You will be able to enjoy the chewy and soft chicken breast much more deliciously.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  닭 가슴살 조리법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사고 방지 대책",
            "option_2"      : "②  사고 대처 방법",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고 발생 원인",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 현장 상황",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I'm currently at the site of Inju-gun where the forest fire occurred. The extinguishing work was finished thirteen hours after the forest fire, but it is a chaotic situation for the residents who lost their homes overnight due to this fire. Inju-gun is preparing temporary accommodation for the affected residents and checking the exact extent of the damage.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  사고 현장 상황",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 집중할 때 손가락을 움직인다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 여자에게 책을 읽어 주고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 남자 때문에 서서 책을 읽는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 남자가 돌아다녀서 집중이 안 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Don't walk around, just sit still and read. I'm out of my mind.\nWoman : If you read it like this, the content will be organized well and it will be memorable for a long time. You also move your fingers when you keep thinking about something.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  남자는 집중할 때 손가락을 움직인다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  중요한 물건은 자신이 보관해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  오전 10시까지는 기숙사에서 나가야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  내일은 하루 종일 기숙사에 들어갈 수 없다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  바닥에 있는 물건을 책상 위로 옮겨야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I would like to inform you from the management office. The dormitory will be cleaned from 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. tomorrow. Please organize all the luggage on the floor and on the desk and keep the important items separately. You can't enter the dormitory during the cleaning and you have to leave by 9:30 a.m. We ask for your active cooperation.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  중요한 물건은 자신이 보관해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 행사는 일주일 동안 진행될 예정이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 행사는 대학생들을 위해서 마련되었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 행사에서는 진학에 관한 정보를 얻을 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 행사의 참가자들은 서로 다른 전공을 가지고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Inju University will hold a major experience event for high school students across the country on August 3rd and 10th. This event is designed to help students decide on a major when they go to college by experiencing the major they are interested in in advance. Participants can actually take classes in their chosen majors and receive further admissions information.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이 행사에서는 진학에 관한 정보를 얻을 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  성격이 비슷하면 빨리 친해진다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  말이 많은 사람과 있으면 불편하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  조용한 성격으로 바뀌었으면 좋겠다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  성격이 다른 사람과 함께 있는 게 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Minsu has an active personality and I think he's really fun.\nWoman : That's right. I have a quiet personality, so it's a little boring to be with someone similar to me. I like it because I talk a lot when I'm with someone who is the opposite of me like Minsu, and I seem to be active.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  성격이 다른 사람과 함께 있는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  과제 마감일을 넘겨서는 안 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  과제는 되도록 일찍 끝내야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  편안한 마음으로 과제를 해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  과제 부담이 크면 과제를 끝내기 어렵다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : The assignment deadline is only two days away, but I really don't want to do it. \nWoman : It's better to do the assignment at that time. If you don't, you'll spend time worrying about the burden. Just because you postpone the assignment until the deadline doesn't mean you can play comfortably.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  과제는 되도록 일찍 끝내야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  서서 하는 회의를 더 자주 해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  서서 회의를 하면 회의에 더 집중할 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  회의 시간에는 서로의 생각을 잘 표현해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  회의에 적극적으로 참여할 수 있는 방법이 필요하다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I heard that the planning team is having a meeting standing up?\nWoman : Yes. It started a while ago and it was good. It's hard to do it for a long time because you're standing. So I don't think about anything else, I concentrate and express my opinions more actively. I think the quality of the meeting is also increasing.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  서서 회의를 하면 회의에 더 집중할 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사람들에게 그림 속 이야기를 들려주어야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그림을 통해 사람의 마음속을 정확하게 알 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  마음의 안정을 얻으려면 그림을 솔직하게 그려야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  그림을 그리면서 마음을 표현하는 효과를 얻을 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that more and more people are treating mental illness through painting. Sir, how can you get peace of mind with painting?\nWoman : Most people who are frustrated or anxious spend a lot of time alone. I'm frustrated and anxious, so I don't have the courage to talk to other people. But if you draw a picture, it has a similar effect to having a conversation. I express the story in my heart with pictures.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  그림을 그리면서 마음을 표현하는 효과를 얻을 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  청소기를 수리한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  신문지를 가지러 간다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  먼지 통을 갈아 준다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  서비스 센터에 전화한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Honey, there's a beep from the vacuum cleaner, isn't it broken?\nMan: I don't think it's broken. Maybe it's because the dust bin is full.\nWoman : Is that so? Then can you change the dust bin?\nMan : Yes, give me the vacuum cleaner.\nWoman : If you just change it, it will drop a lot of dust, so you'd better put a newspaper on the floor.\nMan : OK.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  신문지를 가지러 간다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  수업료를 결제한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  문자 메시지를 보낸다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자에게 신분증을 낸다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자에게서 수업료를 받는다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Well, where should I go for the guitar class?\nWoman : Guitar class? It was canceled, but didn't you get a call? If there are no more than ten applicants, the class won't be held. I contacted you by text message, but there must have been a mistake. I'm sorry.\nMan : I see. Then will you refund the tuition fee?\nWoman : Yes. Did you pay by card by any chance?\nMan: No, I did it in cash.\nWoman: Then can you show me your ID? I'll take care of it right away",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  여자에게 신분증을 낸다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  강사들에게 전화를 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  교육 장소를 다시 찾아본다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  교육 자료가 왔는지 확인한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  강사들에게 교육 장소를 알려 준다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Team leader, the training location for new employees has been decided. It's an auditorium at a nearby university, and I think it would be good because the space is large and the necessary equipment is already installed.\nWoman : Yes, I see. Did you get all the training materials from the instructors?\nMan: No, I told you to send me an email because a few people didn't give me the materials. Woman: Then check it right now and make a call if you haven't come yet.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  교육 자료가 왔는지 확인한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  운행 기사들의 근무 시간을 줄이고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  지하철을 오래 타면 스트레스를 쉽게 받는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  지하철 이용객이 많아져 사고도 늘어나고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  운행 기사들은 사고에 대한 부담감을 가지고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that 85% of the drivers who run the subway are suffering from stress that requires professional treatment. Doctor, what do you think is the cause?\nWoman: There are many things, but the problem is that you stay in a dark place for a long time. As a result of examining the drivers, I was always worried that there would be a big accident. I'm stressed by the idea that even the lives of users can be endangered by a small mistake.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  운행 기사들은 사고에 대한 부담감을 가지고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22.  여자는 누구인지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  정신과 의사",
            "option_2"      : "②  지하철 승객",
            "option_3"      : "③  직업 상담사",
            "option_4"      : "④  지하철 운행 기사",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that 85% of the drivers who run the subway are suffering from stress that requires professional treatment. Doctor, what do you think is the cause?\nWoman: There are many things, but the problem is that you stay in a dark place for a long time. As a result of examining the drivers, I was always worried that there would be a big accident. I'm stressed by the idea that even the lives of users can be endangered by a small mistake.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  정신과 의사",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  잡지의 제작 계획을 밝히고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  잡지의 활용 방안을 제안하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  잡지를 제작하는 과정을 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  잡지를 신청하는 방법을 소개하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I came here because I heard that there is a village where neighbors gathered together to make a magazine. How is 'the story of my neighborhood' made?\nMan : Yes, first of all, we form a group of reporters by accepting applications from the residents. Reporters go around the neighborhood with pictures and interview the residents. I go to every corner of the neighborhood to find information such as food and things to see. When you finish writing the article, take it to the community center and make it into a magazine. It is very popular because the residents collect information themselves and capture their own stories.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  잡지를 제작하는 과정을 설명하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 우리 동네 이야기’가 인기가 있는 이유를 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  주민들이 제작에 참여하기 때문에",
            "option_2"      : "②  사진이 많이 포함되어 있기 때문에",
            "option_3"      : "③  생활 정보가 많이 들어 있기 때문에",
            "option_4"      : "④  주민 센터에서 쉽게 볼 수 있기 때문에",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I came here because I heard that there is a village where neighbors gathered together to make a magazine. How is 'the story of my neighborhood' made?\nMan : Yes, first of all, we form a group of reporters by accepting applications from the residents. Reporters go around the neighborhood with pictures and interview the residents. I go to every corner of the neighborhood to find information such as food and things to see. When you finish writing the article, take it to the community center and make it into a magazine. It is very popular because the residents collect information themselves and capture their own stories.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  주민들이 제작에 참여하기 때문에",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  상담은 편안한 분위기에서 이루어져야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  또래 상담은 상담 기간이 길수록 효과적이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  상담자는 직접적인 해결 방안을 제시해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  또래 상담은 스스로 문제를 찾는 데 효과적이다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWomen : Students usually consult with teachers or experts a lot when they have academic problems, right? However, it may be more effective when you consult with your peers about academic problems. A student attending a Korean middle school said that his grades rose by nearly 10 points on average through peer counseling for one semester. I didn't get help unilaterally, but in the process of talking comfortably with my friend, I found a problem by myself and got a solution. It is said that if you consult with a peer who is having similar concerns, you will see yourself objectively.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  또래 상담은 스스로 문제를 찾는 데 효과적이다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  관찰 결과",
            "option_2"      : "②  자료 조사",
            "option_3"      : "③  구체적인 사례",
            "option_4"      : "④  전문가의 의견",
            "detail"        : "\nWomen : Students usually consult with teachers or experts a lot when they have academic problems, right? However, it may be more effective when you consult with your peers about academic problems. A student attending a Korean middle school said that his grades rose by nearly 10 points on average through peer counseling for one semester. I didn't get help unilaterally, but in the process of talking comfortably with my friend, I found a problem by myself and got a solution. It is said that if you consult with a peer who is having similar concerns, you will see yourself objectively.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  구체적인 사례",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  시민들은 심야 버스의 운행을 반기고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  서울시는 시민의 안전을 위해 노력해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  운송업계는 손해를 보더라도 서울시의 결정에 따라야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  시민들의 경제 사정을 생각해 심야 버스 요금을 내려야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I think expanding the late-night bus in Seoul is a good decision for the convenience and safety of citizens. Citizens really like it because they don't have to worry about bad things going to happen when they leave work late, and they don't get charged more, so they can save on the cost of the car.\nMan: Since the bus runs without such an extra charge, the other transportation industry has a lot of damage. But are you going to increase the operating area in the future? Instead of making such a unilateral decision, I think we should listen to the transportation industry and work together to come up with a way.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  시민들은 심야 버스의 운행을 반기고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 남자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자의 의견에 강하게 반박하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자의 말을 긍정적으로 받아들이고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자의 의견에 대해서 보충 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자의 말에 조심스럽게 문제를 제기하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I think expanding the late-night bus in Seoul is a good decision for the convenience and safety of citizens. Citizens really like it because they don't have to worry about bad things going to happen when they leave work late, and they don't get charged more, so they can save on the cost of the car.\nMan: Since the bus runs without such an extra charge, the other transportation industry has a lot of damage. But are you going to increase the operating area in the future? Instead of making such a unilateral decision, I think we should listen to the transportation industry and work together to come up with a way.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  여자의 의견에 강하게 반박하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  기업의 노력으로 구매율 높아져",
            "option_2"      : "②  새로운 아이디어,소비자의 지갑 열어",
            "option_3"      : "③  구매율 높은 상품을 중심으로 개발해야",
            "option_4"      : "④  신제품 개발,소비자 요구부터 확인해야",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There is fierce competition for ideas to open consumer wallets. But ideas alone are not enough. This is from reporter Kim Min-soo.\nMan : The original, new idea product is enough to attract the attention of consumers. However, it is said that there are few cases that lead to purchase. Experts advise that the first thing to do is to confirm the needs of consumers through market research before developing new products. No matter how interesting the product is, it won't sell well if it doesn't contain what consumers want. When companies develop products, they need to think enough about what consumers want.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  신제품 개발,소비자 요구부터 확인해야",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  차를 대여할 때 보험 문제는 개인적으로 해결해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  가까이 있는 차를 저렴한 가격에 빌릴 수 있어 편리하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  렌터카 회사를 통해서 자가용을 빌리면 대여료가 더 싸다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  개인의 차를 대여해 주다 보면 귀찮은 문제가 많이 생긴다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There is fierce competition for ideas to open consumer wallets. But ideas alone are not enough. This is from reporter Kim Min-soo.\nMan : The original, new idea product is enough to attract the attention of consumers. However, it is said that there are few cases that lead to purchase. Experts advise that the first thing to do is to confirm the needs of consumers through market research before developing new products. No matter how interesting the product is, it won't sell well if it doesn't contain what consumers want. When companies develop products, they need to think enough about what consumers want.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  개인의 차를 대여해 주다 보면 귀찮은 문제가 많이 생긴다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
